[MUSIC]
[음악]
In the regression model, we talked about predicting house prices and
회귀 모델에서는 회귀 모델 맞춤을 통해
fitting a regression model for that and
주택 가격을 예측하고
we measured the error in terms of sum-squared errors.
제곱합으로 오차를 구했습니다
Here in classification, our errors are a little different because we
분류에서는 오차(오류)가 조금 다른데
are talking about what inputs we get correct and which inputs we get wrong.
어떤 입력에 대해 맞고 틀린지를 알아야 하기 때문이죠
So let's talk a little bit about measuring error in classification.
분류의 오류 측정에 대해 좀 더 알아봅시다
So when I learn a classifier, I'm given a set of input data.
분류기를 배울 때 입력 데이터 세트가 주어졌습니다
So these are sentences that have been marked to say positive or negative
긍정적, 부정적인 감성으로 표시된 문장인데
sentiment, and as in regression, we split it into a training set and a test set.
회귀에서와 같이 훈련 세트와 테스트 세트로 나눕니다
I feed the training set to the classifier I'm trying to learn and
훈련 세트를 분류기에 집어넣으면
that algorithm is actually going to learn the weights for words.
알고리즘이 단어 가중치를 학습합니다
So for example it's going to learn that good has a weight 1.0.
예를 들어 좋다가 가중치 1.0,
Awesome, 1.7.
굉장하다 1.7,
Bad, -1.0.
나쁘다 -1.0
And awful, -3.3.
끔찍하다 -3.3이라고 학습합니다
And then, these weights are going to be used to score every element in
그렇게 얻은 가중치로 테스트 세트의 모든
the test set and evaluate how good we're doing in terms of classification.
샘플에 점수를 매겨 분류가 얼마나 정확한지 확인합니다
So lets talk about what that evaluation looks like.
평가가 어떤 식인지 설명드리죠
Let's discuss how we measure error, in fact,
분류 오류 측정을 어떻게 하는지부터
classification error, when we're doing this classification.
짚고 넘어갑시다
So we're getting a set of test examples of the form,
다음의 테스트 예제가 있다고 합시다
sushi was great, is a positive sentence, and we're trying to figure out how many
초밥은 훌륭했다는 긍정적인 문장인데 얼마나 많은 테스트 문장을 맞추고
of these test sentences we get correct and how many do we get make mistakes on.
틀리는지 보죠
So what we are going to do is take the sentence sushi is great and
이제부터 문장 초밥은 훌륭하다를
feed it through the classifier, through the learned classifier.
이미 학습된 분류기에 넣습니다
But we don't want the learned classifier to actually see the true label.
학습된 분류기가 참 라벨을
We're gonna see if it gets the true label right.
보지 않고도 맞추기를 바랍니다
So we're gonna hide that true label.
그러기 위해 참 라벨을 감춥니다
So the sentence gets fed to the learned classifier while the true label is hidden.
참 라벨이 숨겨진 문장이 학습된 분류기에 들어갑니다
And now given the sentence, we're gonna predict y hat as being positive.
문장이 주어졌을 때 y^이 긍정이라고 예측합니다
So we leave this as a positive sentence and so, we've made a correct prediction.
긍정적인 문장이라고 했으니 올바른 예측입니다
So the number of correct sentences goes up by one.
맞은 문장 수가 하나 올라갑니다
Now let's take another sentence, another test example.
다른 문장을 테스트해보죠
So let's say you say the food was okay as a negative sentence.
음식은 그럭저럭이었다는 부정적인 문장입니다
So that's a bit of a ambiguous sentence but
약간 모호한 문장이지만
it's been labeled as negative in the training set.
훈련 세트에서 부정적으로 분류되어 있습니다
So now I feed the sentence to the classifier, I hide the label.
이 문장의 라벨을 감추고 분류기에 넣습니다
And let's see what the classifier does.
분류기가 뭘 하나 지켜보죠
In this case, cuz the food was okay can be revealed as positive,
이 경우 음식은 그럭저럭이었다가
maybe it makes a prediction that this is positive sentence I made a mistake,
긍정적이란 예측을 하면 틀린 것인데
cuz the true label is negative.
실제 라벨은 부정적이기 때문이죠
So say hey, mistake was made.
실수를 했습니다
We now have one more mistake.
실수를 하나 더합니다
So we have one correct classification and one mistake.
올바른 분류 1개와 실수 1개입니다
Now, we do this for every sentence in the corpus.
말뭉치의 모든 문장에 대해 이 테스트를 합니다
There are two common measures of quality in classification.
분류에서는 흔히 쓰는 품질 기준이 두 개 있습니다
So for example, one of them is the notion of error.
하나는 실수를 기준으로 삼습니다
So error measures, the fraction of the test examples that we make mistakes on.
오류 기준은 실수하는 테스트 예제의 비율입니다
So what we just do is say, out of all of the sentences that are classified,
분류된 모든 문장에 대해
how many mistakes there are made, so number of mistakes, and
실수가 몇 개 있었는지 세서
I divide that by the total number of test sentences.
총 테스트 문장 수로 나눕니다
So for example if there were 100 test sentences and
예를 들어 테스트 문장 100개에서
I made ten mistakes then our error would be 0.1 or 10%.
실수가 10개라고 하면 오류는 0.1, 10%입니다
Now the best possible error that I can make is zero basically,
가장 낮은 오류는 0, 그러니까
I make no mistakes.
실수 하나 없는 상태가 되겠죠
Now, it's common to instead of talk about error,
오류 대신에 분류기의 정확도로
to also talk about accuracy of your classifier.
측정하는 경우도 많습니다
So accuracy is exactly opposite of that.
정확도는 정반대지요
So, in accuracy, instead of measuring the number of errors,
정확도에선 오류 개수를 세는 대신에
we measure the number of correct classifications.
올바른 분류의 수를 측정합니다
So the ratio here is number
올바른 분류 수 나누기
of correct divided by total
총 문장 수가
number of sentences.
비율이 됩니다
And unlike error where the best possible value is zero, in terms of accuracy,
따라서 오류와 달리 가장 좋은 수치가 0이
the best possible value is 1, I've got all the sentences right.
아니라 모든 문장을 맞춘 1이 되겠죠
And in fact there's a really natural relationship between the two.
둘 사이에는 당연한 관계가 있습니다
We know that error = 1-
오류 = 1 - 정확도이고
accuracy, and vise versa.
그 반대도 같습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]